Spencer Grant Photographs MS171
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Spencer Grant Photographs
1970 -- 1979
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Grant, Spencer
MS171
.25 Linear Feet 1 box
135 Digital Object(s)
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series.
Custodial History
Mr. Grant sent negatives overseas to have them wet scanned and provided .tifs and .jpgs to DCA. He also sent the original negatives.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of negatives, digital scans and contact sheets for photographs of Tufts University and its students and faculty taken by freelance photographer Spencer Grant.
Related Materials
Spencer Grant Collection. Boston Public Library Flickr page. http://www.flickr.com/photos/boston_public_library/collections/72157627977305452/. Accessed May 15, 2012.
Biographical / Historical
Born in Brooklyn, New York, Spencer Grant graduated in journalism from Boston University in 1966. He worked as Air Force photographer in Nebraska and then as Associated Press photographer in New York. After moving back to Boston in 1969 Spencer worked as freelance photographer for various magazines and services among them United Press International, The Boston Globe, Time magazine, of the Boston magazine. He also did a number of also commercial shoots.
Spencer became Stock Boston photo agency's first photographer in 1971. By the end of the 1970s he worked as a full time stock photographer and, in the late 1970s, he became a stock photographer full-time.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
University history; Tufts University -- History
- Photographs, 1970 -- 1979; MS171.001; 3.6 Linear Feet; 135 Digital Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains digitized images from the 1970s featuring Tufts students, faculty, and landscape.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged by topic.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Tufts and Jackson College alumni socializing at an Alumni Day event, 1973 -- 1978; MS171.001.00001; Grant, Spencer
  - Tufts and Jackson College alumni socializing at a picnic table at an Alumni Day event, 1973 -- 1978; MS171.001.00002; Grant, Spencer
  - Two Jackson College alumnae at Alumni Day event near Class of 1938 sign, 1973 -- 1978; MS171.001.00003; Grant, Spencer
  - Three Jackson College alumnae talking at Alumni Day event under Class of 1938 sign, 1973 -- 1978; MS171.001.00004; Grant, Spencer
  - Three Jackson College alumnae at Alumni Day event under Class of 1938 sign, 1973 -- 1978; MS171.001.00005; Grant, Spencer
  - Three Jackson College alumnae at Alumni Day event under Class of 1938 sign, close-up, 1973 -- 1978; MS171.001.00006; Grant, Spencer
  - Two Jackson College alumnae talking at table during Alumni Day event, 1973 -- 1977; MS171.001.00007; Grant, Spencer
  - Two Jackson College alumnae talking at table near Class of 1938 sign during Alumni Day event, 1973 -- 1978; MS171.001.00008; Grant, Spencer
  - Distance shot of two Jackson College alumnae talking at table during Alumni Day event, 1973 -- 1978; MS171.001.00009; Grant, Spencer
  - Two Class of 1928 alumni walking at Alumni Day event, 1973 -- 1978; MS171.001.00010; Grant, Spencer
    Black people; Alumni and alumnae
  - Tufts and Jackson College alumnae talking under a tree at Alumni Day event, 1973 -- 1977; MS171.001.00011; Grant, Spencer
  - Tufts and Jackson College alumnae laughing under a tree at Alumni Day event, 1973 -- 1978; MS171.001.00012; Grant, Spencer
  - Two Tufts Class of 1928 alumni walking at Alumni Day event near sign, 1973 -- 1977; MS171.001.00013; Grant, Spencer
  - Two Tufts Class of 1928 alumni talking at Alumni Day event, 1973 -- 1978; MS171.001.00014; Grant, Spencer
    African Americans
  - Jackson College student Ellen Lansberger practices at a self-defense class, 1975; MS171.001.00015; Grant, Spencer
  - Jackson College student Ellen Lansberger practices breaking a hold at a self-defense class, 1975; MS171.001.00016; Grant, Spencer
  - Jackson College student Ellen Lansberger practices a kick at a self-defense class, 1975; MS171.001.00017; Grant, Spencer
  - Tufts computer class, 1977; MS171.001.00018; Grant, Spencer
    Computers; Woman; African Americans
  - Tufts faculty conference, 1976; MS171.001.00019; Grant, Spencer
    Note married student with child.
  - Mary Goode, a student in the Continuing Education Program for Urban Women, listens to a lecture, 1974; MS171.001.00020; Grant, Spencer
    Women; Black students
  - Sol Gittleman with student projects including vampire from Nosferatu, 1973 -- 1978; MS171.001.00021; Grant, Spencer
    Tufts German professor Sol Gittleman with his students' class projects including the vampire from the 1922 German film Nosferatu.
    Gittleman, Sol, 1934-
  - Tufts Dean Elizabeth Toupin teaching a cooking class for male students at her house on Professors Row, 1972; MS171.001.00022; Grant, Spencer
    Male students examining the texture of the thin dough used for wrapping dumplings.
    106 Professors Row; Toupin, Elizabeth; Toupin, Liz
  - Dean Elizabeth Toupin teaching an Asian cooking class at her home on Professors Row for male students, 1972; MS171.001.00023; Grant, Spencer
    Toupin, Elizabeth; Toupin, Liz
  - Dean Elizabeth Toupin teaching an Asian cooking class for male students at her home on Professors Row, 1972; MS171.001.00024; Grant, Spencer
  - Dean Elizabeth Toupin demonstrating cutting broccoli, 1972; MS171.001.00025; Grant, Spencer
  - Dean Elizabeth Toupin teaching three male students during an Asian cooking class at her home on Professors Row, 1972; MS171.001.00026; Grant, Spencer
  - Dean Elizabeth Toupin teachers an Asian cooking class for male students at her home on Professors Row, 1972; MS171.001.00027; Grant, Spencer
  - Dean Elizabeth explaining Asian cooking to male students at her home on Professors Row, 1972; MS171.001.00028; Grant, Spencer
  - Three male students assisting Elizabeth Toupin during an Asian cooking class, 1972; MS171.001.00029; Grant, Spencer
  - Dean Elizabeth Toupin, with her son, providing an Asian cooking class to male students, 1972; MS171.001.00030; Grant, Spencer
  - Dean Elizabeth Toupin demonstrating how to chop broccoli, 1972; MS171.001.00031; Grant, Spencer
  - Dean Elizabeth Toupin teaching an Asian cooking class at her home on Professors Row for male students, 1972; MS171.001.00032; Grant, Spencer
  - Dean Elizabeth Toupin instructing male student on how to chop vegetables, 1972; MS171.001.00033; Grant, Spencer
  - Dean Elizabeth Toupin and male student during Asian cooking class, 1972; MS171.001.00034; Grant, Spencer
  - Dean Elizabeth Toupin, with son, instructing male students during Asian cooking class in her home on Professors Row, 1972; MS171.001.00035; Grant, Spencer
  - Dean Elizabeth Toupin and son sample food with male students during Asian cooking class, 1972; MS171.001.00036; Grant, Spencer
  - Overhead view of Asian cooking class held by Dean Elizabeth Toupin, 1972; MS171.001.00037; Grant, Spencer
    A boys-only Asian cooking class taught by Tufts dean Liz Toupin at her home on Professors Row in 1972 works in the kitchen.
  - Dean Elizabeth Toupin working with her son while male student chops vegetables during Asian cooking class, 1972; MS171.001.00038; Grant, Spencer
  - Overhead view of Dean Elizabeth Toupin's Asian cooking class for male students, 1972; MS171.001.00039; Grant, Spencer
  - A Jackson College freshman unpacks in her new dorm room, 1975; MS171.001.00040; Grant, Spencer
  - A Jackson College freshman unpacks in her new dorm room, 1975; MS171.001.00041; Grant, Spencer
  - A Jackson College freshman folds a shirt in her new dorm room, 1975; MS171.001.00042; Grant, Spencer
  - A Jackson College freshman makes up her bed in her new dorm room, 1975; MS171.001.00043; Grant, Spencer
  - Mom joins in as Jackson freshman girls unpack in their new dorm room, 1975; MS171.001.00044; Grant, Spencer
  - Family joins in to help as Jackson freshman girls unpack in their new dorm room, 1975; MS171.001.00045; Grant, Spencer
  - Tufts student makes dinner in a kitchen-equipped dorm room, 1976; MS171.001.00046; Grant, Spencer
    Cookware
  - Tufts students makes dinner in a kitchen-equipped dorm room with cookbook by his side, 1976; MS171.001.00047; Grant, Spencer
  - Two Tufts students reading in their dorm room, 1975; MS171.001.00048; Grant, Spencer
  - Two Tufts students in their dorm room, 1975; MS171.001.00049; Grant, Spencer
  - Two Jackson College freshman unpack in their new dorm room, 1975; MS171.001.00050; Grant, Spencer
  - Three Tufts students at home in their "old building" campus housing, 1975; MS171.001.00051; Grant, Spencer
  - Three Tufts students relaxing in their "old building" campus housing, 1975; MS171.001.00052; Grant, Spencer
  - Jackson College student at home in "old building" campus housing, 1975; MS171.001.00053; Grant, Spencer
  - Jackson College student relaxing at home in "old building" campus housing, 1975; MS171.001.00054; Grant, Spencer
  - Female and male students at home in co-ed campus housing, 1975; MS171.001.00055; Grant, Spencer
  - Newly-arrived Tufts students unpack in their dorm room, 1977; MS171.001.00056; Grant, Spencer
  - A Jackson College student shows off her dorm room wall decoration copied from an art history textbook, 1975; MS171.001.00057; Grant, Spencer
  - A Jackson College student shows off her dorm room wall decoration copied from an art history textbook, 1975; MS171.001.00058; Grant, Spencer
  - Male and female students watch television in their co-ed campus housing, 1975; MS171.001.00059; Grant, Spencer
  - Two female and one male students at home in co-ed campus housing, 1975; MS171.001.00060; Grant, Spencer
  - Two female students and a male student talking at home in co-ed campus housing, 1975; MS171.001.00061; Grant, Spencer
  - Three Tufts students customize their dorm room with electronics and entertainment, 1976; MS171.001.00062; Grant, Spencer
  - Three Tufts students watching television in their dorm room, 1976; MS171.001.00063; Grant, Spencer
  - Two Tufts students relax in chairs in their "old building" campus housing, 1975; MS171.001.00064; Grant, Spencer
  - Two Tufts students customize their dorm room with bunk beds, 1976; MS171.001.00065; Grant, Spencer
  - A Tufts student studies in a customized dorm room with posters, 1976; MS171.001.00066; Grant, Spencer
  - Multiracial group of female students gather to socialize in their dorm room, 1975; MS171.001.00067; Grant, Spencer
    African Americans; Woman
  - Multiracial group of female students socialize in their dorm room, 1975; MS171.001.00068; Grant, Spencer
  - Computerized research with teacher and child at Tufts' Eliot-Pearson Child study center, 1975; MS171.001.00069; Grant, Spencer
    Computers
  - Computerized research at Tufts' Eliot-Pearson Child study center, 1975; MS171.001.00070; Grant, Spencer
    Computer display is of Snoopy.
  - Group research at Tufts' Eliot-Pearson Child study center, 1975; MS171.001.00071; Grant, Spencer
  - Group research at Tufts' Eliot-Pearson Child study center, 1975; MS171.001.00072; Grant, Spencer
  - Participatory research with Norma Canner at Tufts' Eliot-Pearson Child study center, 1975; MS171.001.00073; Grant, Spencer
  - Childrens' teamwork research at Tufts' Eliot-Pearson Child study center, 1975; MS171.001.00074; Grant, Spencer
  - Childrens' reading and listening comprehension research at Tufts' Eliot-Pearson Child study center, 1975; MS171.001.00075; Grant, Spencer
  - Childrens' reading and listening comprehension research at Tufts' Eliot-Pearson Child study center, 1975; MS171.001.00076; Grant, Spencer
  - Children reading outside as part of reading and listening comprehension research at Tufts' Eliot-Pearson Child study center, 1975; MS171.001.00077; Grant, Spencer
  - Childrens' reading comprehension research using projected sentences at Tufts' Eliot-Pearson Child study center, 1975; MS171.001.00078; Grant, Spencer
  - Close-up of children reading outside as part of reading and listening comprehension research at Tufts' Eliot-Pearson Child study center, 1975; MS171.001.00079; Grant, Spencer
  - Close-up of children reading outside as part of reading and listening comprehension research at Tufts' Eliot-Pearson Child study center, 1975; MS171.001.00080; Grant, Spencer
  - Jackson College graduate receives her diploma from Dean Bernie Harleston, 1977; MS171.001.00081; Grant, Spencer
  - Tufts graduate poses with his family, 1977; MS171.001.00082; Grant, Spencer
  - Tufts graduate poses for a photo with his family, 1977; MS171.001.00083; Grant, Spencer
  - Dog joins the Tufts graduation diploma line, 1977; MS171.001.00084; Grant, Spencer
    Note Dean Bernie Harleston at left.
    Black people; African Americans; Dogs; Students
  - President Burton C. Hallowell and Dean Bernie Harleston notice dog in graduation diploma line, 1977; MS171.001.00085; Grant, Spencer
    The dog was identified as Jean Mayer's dog Dudley by Mayer's granddaughter in March 2016. Dudley was given to Mayer by the students in Harvard's Dudley House.
    Dogs; Hallowell, Burton C.
  - Tufts student displays Kretch's Deli shirt under graduation gown, 1977; MS171.001.00086; Grant, Spencer
  - Angled view of Jumbo the elephant, 1973; MS171.001.00087; Grant, Spencer
  - Jumbo the elephant at home in Tufts University's Barnum Hall, 1973; MS171.001.00088; Grant, Spencer
    Note portrait of P.T. Barnum on wall.
    Jumbo
  - Jumbo the elephant with student in Tufts University's Barnum Hall, 1973; MS171.001.00089; Grant, Spencer
    Note bust of P.T. Barnum in background.
  - Jumbo the elephant with student touching trunk, 1973; MS171.001.00090; Grant, Spencer
  - Close-up shot of Jumbo the elephant with student touching trunk, 1973; MS171.001.00091; Grant, Spencer
  - Bust of P.T. Barnum with Jumbo the elephant in the background, 1973; MS171.001.00092; Grant, Spencer
    Jumbo; Barnum, P. T. (Phineas Taylor)
  - Bust of P.T. Barnum with Jumbo the elephant in the background, 1973; MS171.001.00093; Grant, Spencer
  - Bust of P.T. Barnum with student pointing at Jumbo the elephant in the background, 1973; MS171.001.00094; Grant, Spencer
  - Dressed up like clowns Jackson sorority women get ready to entertain local children on Kids Day, 1978; MS171.001.00095; Grant, Spencer
    Chi Omega
  - Dressed up as a clown, a Jackson College student entertains local children on Kids Day, 1978; MS171.001.00096; Grant, Spencer
  - Dressed up as a clown, a Tufts student entertains local children on Kids Day, 1978; MS171.001.00097; Grant, Spencer
  - Dressed up as a clown, a Tufts student entertains local children on Kids Day, 1978; MS171.001.00098; Grant, Spencer
  - A Tufts student plays football with local children on Kids Day, 1978; MS171.001.00099; Grant, Spencer
  - Tufts student plays football with a group of children on Kids Day, 1978; MS171.001.00100; Grant, Spencer
  - Tufts Arena Theatre Magic Circle players pull together in a hands-on show of solidarity, 1979; MS171.001.00101; Grant, Spencer
  - Tufts Arena Theatre Magic Circle players group photograph, 1979; MS171.001.00102; Grant, Spencer
  - Tufts Arena Theatre Magic Circle players put hands together, 1979; MS171.001.00103; Grant, Spencer
  - The cast of Tufts Arena Theatre Magic Circle gather for a photo of "Toad of Toad Hall", 1979; MS171.001.00104; Grant, Spencer
  - The cast of Tufts Arena Theatre Magic Circle gather for a group photo, 1979; MS171.001.00105; Grant, Spencer
  - The cast of Tufts Arena Theatre Magic Circle rehearse "Toad of Toad Hall", 1979; MS171.001.00106; Grant, Spencer
  - The cast of Tufts Arena Theatre Magic Circle rehearse "Toad of Toad Hall", 1979; MS171.001.00107; Grant, Spencer
  - Catholic priest leads students in Ash Wednesday service at Goddard Chapel, 1975; MS171.001.00108; Grant, Spencer
  - Catholic priest blesses Communion table during Ash Wednesday service at Goddard Chapel, 1975; MS171.001.00109; Grant, Spencer
  - Tufts students attend an Ash Wednesday service at Goddard Chapel, 1975; MS171.001.00110; Grant, Spencer
  - Catholic priest consecrates wine during Ash Wednesday service at Goddard Chapel, 1975; MS171.001.00111; Grant, Spencer
  - Catholic priest consecrates wafer during Ash Wednesday service at Goddard Chapel, 1975; MS171.001.00112; Grant, Spencer
  - Catholic nun applies ashes to student's forehead during Ash Wednesday services at Goddard Chapel, 1975; MS171.001.00113; Grant, Spencer
  - Catholic nun dabs ashes on forehead of student during Ash Wednesday services at Goddard Chapel, 1975; MS171.001.00114; Grant, Spencer
  - Catholic nun dabs ashes on the forehead of student in jacket during Ash Wednesday services at Goddard Chapel, 1975; MS171.001.00115; Grant, Spencer
  - Catholic nun dabs ashes on a student wearing a sweater during Ash Wednesday services at Goddard Chapel, 1975; MS171.001.00116; Grant, Spencer
  - A Catholic nun participates in Ash Wednesday services at Goddard Chapel, 1975; MS171.001.00117; Grant, Spencer
  - Tufts and Jackson College students cultivate the soil at the campus Roots and Growth House, 1973; MS171.001.00118; Grant, Spencer
  - Tufts and Jackson College students break up the soil at the campus Roots and Growth House, 1973; MS171.001.00119; Grant, Spencer
  - Tufts and Jackson students till the soil at the campus Roots and Growth House, 1973; MS171.001.00120; Grant, Spencer
  - Tufts and Jackson College students till the soil at the campus Roots and Growth House, 1973; MS171.001.00121; Grant, Spencer
  - Tufts and Jackson College students till the soil at the campus Roots and Growth House, 1973; MS171.001.00122; Grant, Spencer
    At right background is the program's director, Professor Jesper Rosenmeier.
  - Tufts English professor and program director Jesper Rosenmeier cleans up leaves at the campus Roots and Growth House, 1973; MS171.001.00123; Grant, Spencer
  - Tufts English professor and program director Jesper Rosenmeier cleans up leaves at the campus Roots and Growth House, 1973; MS171.001.00124; Grant, Spencer
  - Tufts English professor and program director Jesper Rosenmeier rakes leaves with a student at the campus Roots and Growth House, 1973; MS171.001.00125; Grant, Spencer
  - A Jackson College student cranks a hand freezer to make "academic ice cream" at the campus Roots and Growth House, 1973; MS171.001.00126; Grant, Spencer
  - A Jackson College student cranks a hand freezer to make "academic ice cream" at the campus Roots and Growth House, 1973; MS171.001.00127; Grant, Spencer
  - A Jackson College student cranks a hand freezer to make "academic ice cream" at the campus Roots and Growth House, 1973; MS171.001.00128; Grant, Spencer
  - Program director professor Jesper Rosenmeier assists a Jackson College student cranking a hand freezer to make "academic ice cream" at the campus Roots and Growth House, 1973; MS171.001.00129; Grant, Spencer
  - Tufts and Jackson College students sample hand-made "academic ice cream" at the campus Roots and Growth House, MS171.001.00130; Grant, Spencer
    In background is program director professor Jesper Rosenmeier.
  - Tufts and Jackson College students use a hand crank freezer to make "academic ice cream" at the campus Roots and Growth House, 1973; MS171.001.00131; Grant, Spencer
  - Tufts and Jackson College students use a hand crank freezer to make "academic ice cream" at the campus Roots and Growth House, 1973; MS171.001.00132; Grant, Spencer
  - Tufts Roots and Growth House program director professor Jesper Rosenmeier uses an old-fashioned hand crank freezer to make "academic ice cream", 1973; MS171.001.00133; Grant, Spencer
  - Tufts Roots and Growth House program director professor Jesper Rosenmeier uses a hand crank freezer to make "academic ice cream" with students, 1973; MS171.001.00134; Grant, Spencer
  - Tufts Roots and Growth House program director professor Jesper Rosenmeier uses an old-fashioned hand crank freezer to make "academic ice cream", 1973; MS171.001.00135; Grant, Spencer
  - Two Jackson College students stroll past Ballou Hall, 1975; MS171.001.00136; Grant, Spencer
    Ballou Hall; Woman; Jackson College
  - Negatives, 1970 -- 1979; MS171.001.002 (Box 2)
    10 sheets; former barcode 39090015521392g